<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethan Myers</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ethan Myers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/books/fooledbyrandomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/fooledbyrandomness/</guid>
      <description>Fooled By Randomness, Nicholas Taleb
Fundamentally, the books boils down to the idea that people are shit at estimating risk, and even worse, regularly try to fit a normal model to anything that walks and talks. This results in some pretty funny, if financially catastrophic, fallout.
Fine, fair enough, and a pretty interesting topic for a book. That being said, Taleb&amp;rsquo;s arrogance throughout the book is unnecessary and distracts from his message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clone Juul Pods</title>
      <link>/projects/juulpods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/juulpods/</guid>
      <description>Background Vaping, for better of worse, has supplanted smoking. It&amp;rsquo;s probably less dangerous for you, but the addictive kick still remains.
Chief among the new purveyors of vape is a company called Juul. They make the eponymously named Juul, a device of which anyone under 18 is innately familiar with. They&amp;rsquo;ve got this clean, undeniably sleek, Johnny-Ive-would&amp;rsquo;ve-loved-it dark anodized aluminum aesthetic &amp;ndash; and they&amp;rsquo;re covert to boot. They take a single serve, Keurig-inspired pod, and fill it with proprietary liquid, containing a whopping 59mg of nicotine &amp;ndash; about as much as a pack of cigarettes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decapping microchips for refunds</title>
      <link>/projects/chips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/chips/</guid>
      <description>I buy quite a few microchips from China over the course of any project. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s jellybean parts or branded specialty parts, Aliexpress and eBay have everything imaginable for very attractive prices. That being said, the pedigree of most chips is murky at best, and given a shortage of any part, impostors peddling phony or damaged chips inevitably spring up. The only real way to check if you have the real deal is to pull the die out and check, a time consuming and honestly, kind of dangerous process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milling Machine</title>
      <link>/projects/buying-a-milling-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/buying-a-milling-machine/</guid>
      <description>As I move into more intensive and detailed projects, I increasing need to fabricate custom parts. Normally, I get by with a 3D printer. It has allowed me to make objects far more complex than I can reliably make by hand. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to run up against the limitations of plastic and FDM printing. Even with wondermaterials like PET and HIPS, there&amp;rsquo;s no easy way to build parts for more extreme applications &amp;ndash; high wear or high temperature, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serial VFD</title>
      <link>/projects/vfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vfd/</guid>
      <description>The VFD in its florescent blue glory.   I was rummaging through some junk during my break from school and found some old audio equipment, complete with a VFD for a front panel. I have some spare time on my hands, so I set aside some time to try and get it working. Lo and behold, it&amp;rsquo;s a commercial module &amp;ndash; a CU20025SCPB-T20A from Noritake Itron. This makes things way easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP-12 Programming Jig</title>
      <link>/projects/esp12jig/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/esp12jig/</guid>
      <description>I’m building a small product the uses the ESP8266 chipset to enable mesh networking between a variety of devices. However, I need a way to program them initially, before they go onto the carrier PCB that contains power and peripherals. It’s a pain to try and breadboard or deadbug the 7 or so connections needed to flash new firmware, and both require soldering, something I’m trying to avoid, as they will be soldered in the final assembly and I would like to reduce potential sources of failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Cost Geiger Counter</title>
      <link>/projects/geiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/geiger/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to build an X-ray machine. Not really knowing a ton about x-ray machine design, I decided to dip my toe into the pool of high voltage and dangerous devices with a Geiger counter.
I started with the HV power supply. I&amp;rsquo;m using a SBM-20 tube, and need around 400V across the tube for proper operation. However, it needs a few uA a best, making the design fairly trivial. I opted to use a boost converter, although if I was going to build more than one, I&amp;rsquo;d probably move to a transformer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>